God has no hands but our hands to do His work today.
Prophet T.B. Joshua is moving in the midst of the congregation.
This is not a natural situation but a supernatural battle is taking place
that is a battle of the ages.
But we need not fear as children of God - satan is under our feet.
When the lightning power of God is present as you can see right now,
satan has to bow and flee.
I am the queen.
I destroyed her marriage.
What have you done to her marriage?
Her husband is mine; she married my husband.
I took over the whole man.
Manifestation Of Evil Spirits
STANDARD FOR LIFE
People of God, Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Mrs Tayim Anyaelle.
I am from Cameroon. I'm 26 years of age.
The problem that brought me to The Synagogue Church of All Nations was the problem of anger -
severe anger, spirit of masturbation, lust, pornography and lesbianism.
The anger started from when I lost my parents.
I lost my parents at an early age.
So as a young girl at the age of about 10 years old,
when I lost my mum, I had an aunt who lived in Ghana.
She came for me and my elder brother.
So we went to Ghana to live with her.
She enrolled me to school (GSS). I wrote the GSS examination that year.
I was the best student in the whole of Ghana
My name was even announced on the radio so at that time when you came out the best student,
they would post you to a special school, and the government would pay or give you scholarship.
The scholarship would cater for like 80%,
and your family would just have to pay the remaining few percentage.
My aunt said that she didn't bring me to Ghana to come and go to school.
That's how she stopped my education.
So that anger - that offence - I kept holding on to it.
Excuse me.
So that's how I stopped school.
I became her house help, I was doing all sorts of jobs.
With no panties on, I would do all the work.
She didn't care if I ate or wore pants as a young lady.
This pushed me out and I had to look for friends
that would help me and this is how I got to know men.
After a few years - I spent about ten years in Ghana
and because of this issue I even had a son in Ghana whom I left there.
So I came back to my country - I found a way to come back to my country.
I went back to my mum's elder sister - my aunt.
She sent me back to school (O level); I rewrote my O level examination.
After ten years of not going to school, I registered for the O level.
I still passed my exams.
I registered for eight papers, and I got an A in all the eight papers.
So by the grace of God after the O level, she looked for a way to put me into veterinary school.
But that's not what I wanted to do, but since I had no choice -
you know when you're receiving help from an aunt, you can't command her.
She tells and directs you.
So she put me into veterinary school, and that is science.
I never studied science. I did economics and mathematics.
So I didn't do well in school, I wanted to leave the school.
On one of the holidays, I came to Douala where my elder sister lived.
I spent two weeks holiday with her and by the grace of God, I met my husband.
When I met my husband, we didn't really know each other
because I lived in a different town and he was in Douala.
The school was in Bamenda - in the interior of Bamenda.
After two weeks, I went back to school.
After a month he invited me over, and he proposed to me and we got married.
That's how we just got married.
I didn't know him as we didn't go through courtship
so I didn't get to know him and he didn't know me either.
We didn't know the other's weaknesses.
It was in the marriage that we got to know each other.
When I got into his home, he would go to work,
and I was a housewife, I was at home.
I'll go through his computer, his laptop.
I discovered that there were so many pornographic pictures of ladies, naked women on it.
I became so jealous.
I wondered, why would my husband be watching other women when I'm here?
Even when I deleted those phonographic pictures, he would still put them back.
So that is how the anger started.
Instead of me to be more prayerful as a wife and not to keep offence
like the man of God always teaches,
I fought the battle physically, I would use a knife on him.
I did so many wrong things to my husband.
Okay, it is indeed a pathetic situation.
It's an experience in life and we thank God Almighty that the end result is a big testimony.
Okay.
Because of the anger, if you look at the body of my husband, you will see marks.
It pushed me to use knives on him.
There was one time I gave him a wound here,
that made him stay in the hospital for almost a month,
because the knife touched his vein and the bleeding was so much.
There was one time I chased him with a knife because I wanted to cut off his penis.
I held his penis and he had to run away from me.
He jumped from a two-storey building just to run away from me.
This anger made my husband not to come back home because he was scared of me.
He would not want to come back home.
Even till now, we don't sleep together.
He sleeps in his own room, and I sleep in mine.
He doesn't want to eat my food anymore.
So many things have happened, I offended him.
It made me to put him into so many debts
because all the houses we stayed in, they already knew us in Douala.
The fight was too much, every estate that we stayed in knew us.
I would fight to the extent where - if that anger did not see blood, it would not stop.
I broke people's properties.
They couldn't hold me accountable as a housewife so they would always hold him accountable.
All his salary would go towards paying people's houses, properties and debts.
I'm so sorry, my husband.
We know that indeed, you are so sorry because
that very demon that brought about the spirit of anger is out of your life.
But before you tell us your testimony and how you were delivered,
we still want to learn more from your life experience,
Can you tell us precisely how this spirit of anger actually affected your relationship with your children?
Yes, I have a three-year-old daughter.
One day she came to me in the morning because she eats a lot.
She came to me and was crying, "Mum, please, I'm hungry".
At that period I was so lonely.
I would lock myself up in the room and masturbate myself.
I would not even care if my children had eaten - nothing.
I would lock myself in. Sometimes I would come out of the room when it is already passed lunch.
I didn't care if my children had eaten.
So this small girl - this is her picture here -
she'll come crying to me, "Mummy, I'm hungry".
I would tell her, "Oh, go to your uncle" because I live with my junior brother.
I would say, "Go to your uncle for him to prepare something for you to eat".
She kept coming come to me.
That day - I had a huge mirror in my room -
she used her leg to hit the mirror and it got broken.
That anger just came upon me, and I beat up that child until I broke her leg.
How old was she then?
At that time she was I think two years old - yes, almost two.
She could not walk.
I saw that the problem was too much. It was controlling me.
Even this problem of lesbianism - it pushed me out to meet girls that were lesbians.
I didn't know but through their conversation they initiated me into lesbianism.
When one of them mentioned the name initiation, that's when the thought of it came.
I said to myself, "No, these people are going to initiate me", so I stopped going there.
But they kept coming to my home and in my dreams too, I would see myself with women.
So this also made me to lose the affection that I had for my husband.
When I saw women physically, I would start admiring women.
I no longer admired my husband.
So last week when the man of God touched me, that's when I started manifesting.
This anger started manifesting in me and it spoke all.
Now I'm delivered. That spirit is gone.
Shall we clap for wonderful Jesus Christ!
To God be the glory! Right now the spirit of anger is gone after the deliverance. Is that correct?
Yes, it's totally gone. Even the urge for masturbation, pornography is totally gone!
My dreams are free.
To God be the glory.
When the story of her pathetic situation was narrated to the man of God,
he went further to invite the husband and to the glory of God her husband is right here in our midst.
Mrs Tayim Anyaelle
Deliverance Testimony
Please, Man of God, help me to reconcile my marriage.
My husband said that this marriage is not from God and he is going to divorce me.
Please help me, Man of God.
Restore my marriage and bless it.
Please, Man of God, beg my husband for me to forgive me.
I didn't know what I was doing.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Jude Tayim.
I come from Cameroon.
I am a Cameroonian by birth and nationality.
I got married to my wife about five years ago.
As she said, we met in September and got married in December that year.
So we never took time to get to know each other.
It is only when we were inside the marriage that we started to know the other's weaknesses.
Seriously, what I would like to say is that: If this is how marriage is like,
then I would advise no one to get married.
It's with respect to what I'm facing because the heat is extreme.
I don't think that anyone of you could accept to face that type of heat.
I will share with you today some bitter experiences that I've been facing.
I jumped from a storey building because I was running for my life
as my wife, out of anger, was chasing me with a knife in an attempt to kill me.
So I jumped from a storey building. I fell down and broke my leg.
I ran out of the house and stayed out for two weeks.
I came back later, thinking things had calmed.
At times, she got very annoyed.
Whenever I said anything, she would never agree with me.
She always wanted to command in the house.
Whenever she saw some funny videos on my phone or my computer,
it activated her anger, and she started fighting with me.
Whenever we fought, she always wanted to wound me.
When she did not find a weapon to wound me, she would use her teeth.
I have different marks on my arms.
Things like this.
Mr Jude Tayim
Shares Life Experience
I came back from work one day.
She started harassing me, asking why I was having pornographic videos on my phone.
I did not even have the time to explain why the videos were there.
So we started fighting and she took a knife.
She wanted to pierce me and I tried to block the knife. Then she cut my hand.
I went to the hospital and they sew it.
This other one here was a bottle.
She broke a bottle - a bottle of beer - and she pierced me with the bottle.
It affected my vein, and I lost so much blood.
I went to the hospital and I was admitted there for almost one month.
My condition was very extreme.
So this other one...
These marks are from different incidents. There are many of them.
This other one was also a bottle.
She broke a bottle and cut me with it everywhere.
I decided to separate my room from her because one day, when I was sleeping, I suddenly collapsed.
When I got up, I realized that whilst I had been sleeping, she had come with a weapon and hit me.
So I got up. It was her junior brother and my junior brother that came and tried to resuscitate me.
So I said to myself that I cannot live in this kind of condition because I don't know the future.
The future may be more dangerous than that.
So I decided that she should sleep in the matrimonial home,
and I would look for another room and sleep there.
Anytime I slept, I would lock the door.
I locked the door because I was afraid
that when a person would annoy her, she would pour her anger on me.
Another experience was that when I came back home one day,
I found my two-years-old daughter not walking.
Whenever I came back from work, she would say, "Daddy, Daddy" and would come and hug me.
But that day she did not come, she was very sad.
I asked, "What is happening with this baby?"
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I know you have a lot to say.
I want to tell the viewers all over the world that I will not allow this family to go,
until we have reached an agreement with God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TESTIMONY TIME
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Mrs Tayim Anyaelle.
I'm from Douala, Cameroon.
The gentleman beside me is my lovely husband.
I came to The SCOAN with a problem of anger - severe anger.
This problem really cost me a lot because it affected my marriage and my relationship with my children.
It especially affected my marriage because the fights were too much with my husband.
All his body is full of marks because when I was angry, I would use a knife - sharp objects - to wound him.
I came to the church, and I was opportune to be placed on the prayer line.
When the man of God touched me, that spirit manifested and I was delivered by the grace of God.
The following week, after discussing with the man of God, he invited my husband over.
He also received deliverance.
I admit that I have been a bad partner,
and I thank God today that I am saved, delivered and happy.
The anger is gone. I am free.
When we met the man of God, he spoke to my husband and pleaded for me.
He told my husband that for us to enjoy light, we must experience darkness.
The devil fought us because there is joy ahead.
Because of that joy, that light that he had seen,
the devil always fought us because of our future.
He had seen the bright future, joy ahead. That is why he was fighting this marriage.
But by the grace of God, this marriage is from God.
We have reconciled. I love my husband very much.
I really want to begin by thanking the man of God
because ever since we've been here, he's been taking good care of us - my husband and I.
The teachings, the meditations and all the prayers - I really want to thank the man of God.
He's been taking care of us spiritually, physically, emotionally -
in every aspect we've been comfortable.
I've never felt at home in my whole life like I have felt here.
Indeed the teachings have taught me a lot in life.
So many things I did not know about Christianity.
I thought Christianity was just about going to church on Sundays,
and when you have time you read your Bible.
But now I know Christianity is when you build a relationship with God.
You cannot say you love your husband, or you love your children, if you don't love God
because true love comes from God.
It's that love that flows from God before you can extend it to your family.
So I have learnt a lot, and I see myself now as a wife.
I even pray for my husband - more than I pray for myself.
I pray for my children.
I thank God for the faith bracelet. It helps me to build my faith.
I always find myself praying more.
This is something that I've never really been doing before.
This is what I should have been doing - fighting spiritually.
Like what the man of God has been saying: Our battles are spiritual battles.
We cannot use the physical to fight the spiritual.
In terms of your relationship with your husband,
how have you been relating with him since your deliverance and the reconciliation?
Oh, it has really been good - peaceful. Now I understand him more.
Whenever I say something, all of a sudden I get conscious that it is wrong.
I say, "Oh baby, you know I love you, I am sorry".
Things have really been more calm.
The conversation flows. I tell him I love him every day, but before I didn't do that.
I now ask him in the morning, "Have you eaten?"
I sometimes even go to get his food - for lunch or breakfast.
I take care of him. I was never doing that before.
I did not even care when he came back from work or what time he came home.
Before, I would just lock myself up in the room.
My heart is full of joy and peace. I'm so happy being around here -
it's like Heaven on earth.
My name is Jude Tayim. I come from Cameroon.
The beautiful lady beside me is my lovely wife.
I came here last week on Sunday.
The man of God also prayed for me.
He said that many marriages have collapsed because the devil always fights people spiritually.
He said that the devil saw the greater joy ahead of us.
That is why the devil was trying to create all this destruction
so that we would not achieve that joy that God had destined for us.
That was his word. And he said that this marriage is a marriage from God.
I have witnessed many changes.
I did things deliberately just to see her reactions.
One of the things that I did on the first day:
I was poorly dressed and she asked me to go and dress up.
I said to myself, "This is an opportunity for me to see if this girl is really delivered from that spirit of anger".
So I refused to go and dress up.
I saw how she reacted: She ignored me.
I said to myself, "Oh, thank You, God", and I later went and changed.
Another experience I had was that she has been asking me to buy a Bible.
That I cannot grow in my spiritual life without having a Bible.
I know that what she said is a very good and wonderful idea.
I will not leave Nigeria without having a Bible.
But I told her that she should not disturb me with this issue of Bible.
That I will have the Bible at my own time.
I thought that that would make her mad but fortunately, she was still calm.
The things that before would have caused anger - you realized that she was just calm.
She was not reacting to what you were doing?
All those things that would previously activate her anger are deactivated.
Now she is controlled by another spirit - that is, the Holy Spirit -
thanks to Prophet T.B. Joshua who came into our lives and intervened.
This is a wonderful marriage.
I just believe that we will achieve our goal as the man of God said.
We will live to see that happiness, and we will come back here for another greater testimony.
What I can say about myself is that:
I came here, and I had the spirit of watching too much pornography, that is lust.
Since the time the man of God laid his hand on me...
He was talking about how he will just give everybody a friendly tap.
But he arrived at my side and he gave me a touch:
My eyes became red as if I had just been smoking weed.
I tried to look at the man and thought he had hammered my head.
I said to myself, "That if that was just a simple touch, why am I feeling as if he had a metal in his hand?"
The next day, I decided to start browsing on my phone.
I went onto Facebook and the truth is that:
The things I saw then - a picture that was not good.
It was not really good for a Christian and automatically when I saw this picture,
there was an awareness in me and I received a revelation,
"That what you are about to watch is not in accordance with God's principles.
Do you accept or do you reject?" I just rejected it.
This really proved that the spirit that was pushing me into this thing,
that made me feel that watching this pornography was normal,
that spirit has left and I have regained consciousness.
I don't have any urge again.
I don't have any urge - neither to watch pornography nor lust for women.
For the few days that I have been here, I've learned so many things that I never knew about.
I thought Christianity was maybe just about reading the Bible - that was all.
But I never knew that Christianity is a lifestyle.
What I can advise the viewers all over the world is that we should always have our Holy Bible with us.
And as the man of God says, the Holy Bible is not that book that we carry.
The Holy Bible is that scripture that we read and we make it an integral part of us.
We read, swallow and digest it into our system - our spiritual system.
So that at any moment in our life when we are faced with any form of temptation,
the words can easily flow out from our hearts.
So we should make God's Word the standard for our life.
My encouragement to all Emmanuel viewers, both here and outside in the whole world,
is that indeed, marriage is not a bed of roses.
Like Prophet T.B. Joshua always says:
It is two imperfect people who have come together to create a union.
We need to understand each other more and be more patient.
And like my husband has said: Make the Word of God the standard for your life.
I also want to advise women - mothers and married women:
When you get into marriage, don't think that the devil will just let you enjoy it -
that every day, there will just be roses and honeymoon.
Indeed, there will be certain challenges.
But instead of fighting them physically - like what I did, the mistake I did -
it is preferable and even the best way to go down on your knees - like the teachings I got here -
go into your room and fight all your battles on your knees.
Pray for your husband, pray for your children,
and avoid friends outside, friends who add nothing to your life but instead divide and subtract.
We pray that God will give both of you the grace to maintain what you have received here
by making the Word of God the standard for your life.
We believe as you do say, the best is yet to come, in Jesus' name.
Thank You, Jesus.
Mr & Mrs Jude Tayim
Family Reconciliation Testimony